KAYLA E. SMITH

JUNIOR FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

kaylaesmith1@gmail.com +34 663 539 379 LinkedIn GitHub Website

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a junior fullstack developer, experienced in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Python with some knowledge of React and Angular. After working as a researcher in the Public Health sector for over six years, I decided to broaden my skill set and embark on a career as a frontend developer. I thrive in a fast-paced environment and strive to solve problems efficiently, whether on my own or as part of a team.

KEY SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, React

Version Control: GitHub, Git, Heroku
 Frameworks: Bootstrap, Django, Netlify

EDUCATION

July 2022 – present Code Institute

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development | (online) Credit Rated by the University of the West of Scotland

Sept 2012 – June 2015 Universitat Pompeu Fabra

Master of Public Health | (Barcelona, Spain)

Sept 2006 - May 2010 University of Iowa

Bachelor of Arts in Global Health & Spanish | (Iowa, USA)

PORTFOLIO PROJECTS

Iowa State Fair – Three-page website about the Iowa State Fair.
 Technologies Used - HTML, CSS | GitHub - State Fair Project

Sea Creature Memory - Interactive memory game.

Technologies Used - HTML, CSS, JavaScript | GitHub - Sea Creature Memory

Hangman – Interactive hangman game.

Technologies Used - Python, Heroku | GitHub - Python Hangman

The Wine Garden BnB – Website for a faux bed and breakfast company.

Technologies Used - HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Heroku, Django | GitHub - The Wine Garden BnB

WORK EXPERIENCE

May 2021 - Sept 2022

Oct8ne | Barcelona, Spain

Tech Support

- Identify and solve technical issues that arise for customers.
- Improve the UI/UX through creation of custom designs and features for clients using SQL, Visual Studio and Angular.
- Impart basic technical information to clients to ensure seamless implementation and functionality of Oct8ne technology on their website(s).

Sept 2013 - present

Translator and Proofreader | Barcelona, Spain

Freelance

Translate from Spanish or Catalan to English for scientific documents related to healthcare. Editor for information
and use of English for scientific articles before their submission to scientific journals for publication.

June 2017 - June 2020

Agency for Health Quality and Assessment of Catalonia | Barcelona, Spain

Public Health Researcher

- Write reports for the Spanish Ministry of Health concerning such topics as joints (shoulder, hip and knee) and enteral nutrition.
- Evaluate innovative projects and research proposals seeking financial assistance through public government funding.
- Create and disseminate reports and plans of action to local and national governments for Catalan healthcare facilities under pressure and time constraints dealing with the Covid-19 pandemic.

CERTIFICATES

• SheCodes Online Workshops

(Introduction to Coding - Oct 2020; Front End Development - Dec 2020; React - Feb 2021)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Currently learning React and completing the Code Institute course framework
- Languages: English (native), Catalan (C2), Spanish (C2), German (B2, working towards C1)
- Based in Barcelona, Spain but willing to relocate. Residency and work permission for the EU and US.

INTERESTS

- Women in tech groups (slack channels, MeetUps, etc)
- Collaborative coding opportunities (Hackathons)
- Cooking / Baking / Travel / Knitting & Crochet / NFL